Inventory of the Hardin Blair Jones papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Hardin Blair Jones papers
1949-1976
79101
Jones, Hardin Blair, 1914-
75 manuscript boxes (30 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, writings, reports, memoranda, clippings, leaflets, and other printed matter, relating to student radicalism, primarily at the University of California at Berkeley.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1979.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
American physiologist; assistant director, Donner Laboratory, University of California, Berkeley, 1948-1975.
Scope and Content of Collection
The papers of the American physiologist and assistant director of the Donner Laboratory at the University of California, Berkeley from 1948 to 1975 include correspondence, writings, reports, memoranda, clippings, leaflets, and other printed matter, relating to student radicalism, primarily at the University of California at Berkeley.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
University of California, Berkeley.; Radicalism--United States.; Student movements--United States.
Collection Contents
- Drafts (Box 1)
- Art class displays. (Box 1)
- Miscellany (Box 1)
- Davis, Angela (Box 1)
- Letters from the public (Box 1)
- Survey Research Center (Box 1)
- Jones, Alexander Grendon and William Petersen - letters and writings (Box 1)
- Letters from readers (Box 2)
- Jones - correspondence (Box 2)
- Coombs, Kenneth (Box 2)
- Commonwealth Club (Roger Heyns Nov. 1965) (Box 2)
- Photographs (Box 2)
- Pauley, Edwin. (Box 2)
- Academic misconduct (Box 3)
- Arnon, Daniel - letters (Box 3)
- Beahrs, Dick. (Box 3)
- Beard, Helen (Box 3)
- Belyea, Richard (Box 3)
- Bolton, EarlC. (Box 3)
- Boyd, Phillip (Box 3)
- Bramstedt, William (Box 3)
- Brodin, N.Eric (Box 3)
- Blake, Robert Pierpont (1886-1950) (Box 3)
- Buckley, William F., Jr. (Box 3)
- Campus Crusade for Christ (Box 3)
- Carter, Edward (Box 3)
- Chancellors - letters to and from (Box 3)
- Combs, R. E. (Box 3)
- Cleaveland, Brad (Box 3)
- Crocker, George N. (Box 3)
- Davidson, Garrison (Box 4)
- DeCourcy, John (Intelligence Digest, 1969) (Box 4)
- D'Evelyn, Thomas M. (Box 4)
- Finch, Rober tH. (Box 4)
- Grant, Allan (Box 4)
- Grendon, Alexander (Box 4)
- Haldane, J. B. S. (Box 4)
- Hearst, Catherine (Box 4)
- Hershey, General LewisB. (Box 4)
- Heyns, Chancellor Roger (Box 4)
- Higgs, DeWitt A. (Box 4)
- Hoffer, Eric (Box 4)
- Hucul, Walter (Box 4)
- Hudson, William (Box 5)
- Jones - letters and clippings (Box 5)
- Jones, Grendon and Louisell, "An American Prospectus for Peace and Freedom" (Box 5)
- Jones, Don (Box 5)
- Johnston, John (Box 5)
- Jukes, Thomas H. (Box 5)
- Kidner, Frank (Box 5)
- Langer, Elinor (Box 5)
- Leibman, Morris I. (Box 5)
- Pornography (Box 5)
- DeCourcy, John, "The University of California: A Shocking Story, " Intelligence Digest, Feb. 1968 (Box 5)
- Levin, Bernard, "Make No Mistake, America Is Fighting for Us, " Daily Mail, Feb. 1, 1968 (Box 5)
- Heyns, Chancellor Roger, letter to, June 14, 1968 (Box 5)
- Jones, "Professor Looks at UC Students," San Francisco Examiner, Aug. 30, 1968 (Box 5)
- Communist resolution (Box 5)
- Nixon, Richard M., telegram to, July 25, 1970 (Box 6)
- Heyns, Chancellor Roger (Box 6)
- Horowitz, Harold W., vs. Jones, Oct. 6, 1969 (Box 6)
- University heads (Box 6)
- Kennedy, Laurence J. (Box 6)
- Civil rights analysis (Box 6)
- Jones - letter to Honolulu Advertiser (Box 6)
- State government notes (Box 6)
- Miscellany (Box 6)
- Academic reform and rules (Box 6)
- Grendon, Alexander (Box 6)
- Potter, Paul, talk at Hotel Claremont (Box 6)
- Grendon, Alexander, analyst, Section 31 (Box 6)
- Jones - notes (Box 6)
- Jones - writings (Box 7)
- Strong, Edward (Box 7)
- Faculty writings on Berkeley (Box 7)
- Free Speech Movement rally, Dec. 1964 (Box 7)
- Faculty solution to Free Speech Movement (Box 7)
- Faculty opposition to Free Speech Movement (Box 7)
- Faculty petitions (Box 7)
- Feuer, Lewis (Box 7)
- Free Speech Movement analysis - Kathleen Gales (Box 7)
- Free Speech Movement - Notes (Box 7)
- Free Speech Movement - Faculty (Box 7)
- Academic Senate (Box 7)
- Academic Senate Emergency Executive Committee (Box 7)
- Burns, Hugh - report (Box 7)
- DuBois·club (Box 8)
- Communism, 1956-1967 (Box 8)
- Space sciences (Left) (Box 8)
- Miscellany (Box 8)
- Printed matter (Box 9)
- Behnke, Dr. Albert R., Jr. (Box 9)
- Canaday, John (Box 9)
- Heyns, Chancellor Roger (Box 9)
- Miscellany (Box 9)
- Bundy, McGeorge, letter to (KQED) (Box 9)
- Santa Barbara and San Diego (Box 9)
- Campus Studies Institute (Box 9)
- Campus problems of unrest, Spring 1970 (Box 9)
- Chytil, Renatur R. J. (Box 9)
- Davis, Angela (Box 9)
- Davis, George (Box 9)
- Terrorism (Box 9)
- Feuer, Lewis, 1969 (Box 9)
- Hayakawa, Dr. S. I. (Box 9)
- Hitch, President Charles J. (Box 10)
- Ford Foundation (Box 10)
- Heyns, Roger (Box 10)
- Miscellany (Box 10)
- Berkeley - People's Park - Folder 8, 1971 (Box 10)
- Berkeley - People's Park - Folder 7, 1969-1970 (Box 10)
- Berkeley - People's Park - Folder 3, June 1969 (Box 10)
- Berkeley - People's Park - Folder 5, July-Dec. 30, 1969 (Box 11)
- Berkeley - People's Park - Folder 4, "People's Pad" Issue (Box 11)
- Berkeley - People's Park - Folder 6, Grand jury indictments, 1970 (Box 11)
- Berkeley - People's Park - Folder 2, May 24-30, 1969 (Box 11)
- Berkeley rent strike - University community activists and property owners, Aug. 1969 (Box 11)
- Berkeley city schools in relation to university community activism (Box 11)
- "Berkeley Three" (Peter Camejo, Paul Glusman, Jack Bloom) (Box 12)
- Berkeley - Uprising of June 28 - July 4, 1968 (2 Folders) (Box 12)
- Berkeley - People's Park - Folder 1, Apr. 28 - May·23, 1969 (Box 12)
- Miscellany (Box 12)
- Donner Laboratory Division of Medical Physics and Clark Kerr (Box 13)
- Miscellany (Box 13)
- Grendon, Alexander - "Little Notes" (Box 13)
- Honolulu Advertiser a letter by Jones (Box 13)
- Kerr, Clark, "The Turmoil in Higher Education," Look, Apr. 18, 1967 (Box 13)
- Norpel, John R., Jr. (Box 13)
- LSD incident, Berkeley - Letter to Alameda grand jury (Box 13)
- Notes on resolution of Dec. 8, 1964 (Box 13)
- Loyalty oath (Box 14)
- California Monthly (Box 14)
- Miscellany (Box 14)
- Pauling, Linus (Box 14)
- Pine, Mr. (American Legion) (Box 14)
- Political disturbances (Box 14)
- Stocking, George (Box 14)
- Wofsy, Leon (Box 14)
- Wachter, Douglas (Box 14)
- Katz, Eli (Box 14)
- Katz (Eli) case - Notes by Edward Strong (Box 15)
- Katz case (Box 15)
- Miscellany (Box 15)
- Hoover, J. Edgar (Box 15)
- Printed matter (Box 15)
- Radical leaflets (Box 15)
- Radical leaflets (Box 16)
- Printed matter (Box 16)
- Printed matter (Box 17)
- Radical leaflets (Box 17)
- Radical leaflets (Box 18)
- Miscellany (Box 18)
- Grendon, Alexander (Box 19)
- Miscellany (Box 19)
- Los Angeles Times, letter to, July 29, 1968 (Box 19)
- U. C. Berkeley Main Library - Handout from information desk, 1970 (Box 19)
- Betts, Robert (Box 19)
- Buckley, William F., Jr. (Box 19)
- Campus Draft Opposition (Box 19)
- Hunt, H. L. (Box 19)
- London School of Economics - London Times and Observer articles (KennethCoombs) (Box 19)
- Richter, Les (Box 19)
- Shaw, Stanford (Box 19)
- Methvin, Eugene H. (Box 19)
- Loeffler, Ted (Box 19)
- Freedom Studies Center (Box 19)
- Palmer, H. Bruce (Box 19)
- Palmer, H. Bruce - Visit (Box 19)
- (Box 20)
- Drugs (Box 20)
- Jones, "Campus Reds: Tools of Their Masters," (Reply to Harold Horowitz), Oct. 13, 1969 (Box 20)
- University of California centennial (Box 20)
- FBI, letter to (Box 20)
- Strike, 1969 (Box 20)
- Radicalism (Box 20)
- Hershey, General Lewis B. (3 folders) (Box 20)
- Heyns, Chancellor Roger - Speech, 1967 (Box 21)
- Jones - Writings (Box 21)
- Miscellaneous letters (Box 21)
- Searle, John (Box 21)
- Warren, Earl (Box 21)
- Hitch, President Charles J. (Box 21)
- Higgs, DeWitt A. (Box 21)
- Academic Senate - Committee reports (Box 21)
- Academic Senate - Committee reports, 1968 (Box 21)
- Buckley, William F., Jr. (Box 21)
- Setinberg, Leigh (Box 21)
- Berlandt, Konstantin (Box 21)
- Black Panthers (Box 21)
- Miscellany (Box 21)
- Black Panthers, 1968-1969 (Box 22)
- Black Students Union (Box 22)
- Bombings (Box 22)
- Bowker, Chancellor Albert, 1971 (Box 23)
- Boyd, Vice Chancellor William (Box 23)
- Brown, Edmund G. (Box 23)
- Bulletin board, U. C. (Box 23)
- Burns, Hugh (California State Senator) - 13th - report on un - American activities in California and supplement (Box 23)
- Byrne (Jerome C.) report (Box 23)
- Campus Draft Opposition (2 folders) (Box 23)
- California Conservatives for Political Action (Box 23)
- Cal Prep (Box 23)
- Cal Prep, Fall1966 (Box 23)
- Cal Student Speakers Program, 1966 (Box 23)
- Cambodia protest, May 1970 (Box 23)
- Campus Draft Opposition - Antiwar movement and Vietnam Commencement (Box 23)
- Miscellany (Box 24)
- Miscellany (Box 25)
- Miscellany (Box 26)
- Berkeley Study Committee on Education (Box 26)
- Miscellany (Box 27)
- University of California directories (Box 27)
- Congressional hearing transcripts (Box 27)
- Associated Students of the University of California minutes, 1967-1968 (Box 27)
- Associated Students of the University of California Senate minutes, 1968-1969 (Box 28)
- University of California Academic Senate Record (Northern Section), 1957-1960 (Box 28)
- University of California Academic Senate Record (Northern Section), 1960-1963 and 1967 (Box 29)
- University of California Academic Senate Record (Northern Section), 1954-1957 and 1968 (Box 30)
- Stripp, Fred (Box 31)
- Students for a Democratic Society, 1965-1971 (Box 31)
- Student conduct (Box 31)
- Student fees (Box 31)
- Student government, Brief account of (Box 31)
- Student governance report (Foote) (Box 32)
- Student Mobilization Committee (Box 32)
- University Students for Law and Order (Box 32)
- Student protests, 1969-1971 (Box 32)
- Student protests, (discussions), 1965-1968 (Box 33)
- Student rules (Box 33)
- Student Non-Violent Coordinating Committee, and farm labor pickets (Box 33)
- Student rights (Box 33)
- Supreme Court (Box 33)
- Susskind, Charles (Box 33)
- Synapse (Box 33)
- Syndicalism (Box 33)
- Levin, Bernard, "Make No Mistake, America Is Fighting for Us,", 1968 (Box 33)
- Louisell, David W., "Responding to the December 8th Resolution: Of Politics, Free Speech, and Due Process,", 1966 (Box 33)
- Kerr, Clark, "The Turmoil in Higher Education,", 1967 (Box 33)
- Hacker, Andrew, "Philosopher of the New Left,", 1968 (Box 34)
- Montgomery, Ed, "Chapter and Verse of California's New Left,", 1966 (Box 34)
- San Francisco Mime Troupe (Box 34)
- Gardner, Fred, "Outspoken Critic of Demonstrations: UC Regent Pauley" (Box 34)
- Petersen, William, "Faculty Rebellion at Berkeley" (Box 34)
- Petersen, William - miscellaneous writings (Box 34)
- Petersen, William, "What Remains of Liberal Education?" (Box 34)
- Petersen, William, "What's left at Berkeley?", 1965 (Box 34)
- Teller, Edward, "Planning for Peace, " 1967, and "The Chinese Hydrogen Bomb" (Box 34)
- Susskind, Charles - remarks, 1966 (Box 34)
- Sherriffs, Alex C., "Convenient Myths about Today's Students,", 1967 (Box 34)
- Srong, E. W., "What's Ahead for the University?" (Box 34)
- University of California Academic Senate miscellany (Box 34)
- "Current Communist Goals" (Box 34)
- Anderson, Tom, "Dear Brats,", 1969 (Box 34)
- Grendon, Alexander, Hardin B. Jones, and William Petersen, "Crisis at Berkeley,", 1965 (Box 35)
- Grendon, Alexander, letter to the editor, 1965 (Box 35)
- Grendon, Alexander, press conference, 1966 (Box 35)
- Hook, Sidney, "Second Thoughts on Berkeley,", 1965 (Box 35)
- Hook, Sidney, "Student Revolts Could Destroy Academic Freedom,", 1968 (Box 35)
- Hook, Sidney, "Democracy Doesn't Work on Campus,", 1968 (Box 35)
- Jones, Hardin B., "A Short Report on the Political Disturbances at Berkeley and Their Effects" (Box 35)
- Lepawsky, Albert, "Academic Freedom and Political Liberty,", 1965 (Box 35)
- Ecology (Box 35)
- Educational Opportunities Program (Box 35)
- Economic Opportunity Organization - Berkeley Area (Box 35)
- Education, 1966-1970 (Box 36)
- Educational reform (Box 36)
- Elberg, Sanford S. (Box 36)
- Elskie letters (Box 36)
- Ergo (Box 36)
- Ethnic matters (Box 36)
- Experimental college (Berkeley) (Box 36)
- Berkeley Faculty for Brown (Box 36)
- Faculty documents (Berkeley), 1964-1965 (Box 36)
- Faculty Forum (Box 37)
- Faculty mailings - Left (Box 37)
- Faculty - Student report on university governance (Berkeley) (Box 37)
- Farm labor agitation (Box 37)
- Federal Bureau of Investigation (Box 37)
- Filthy speech movement (Box 37)
- Finkelstein, Jacob J. (Box 37)
- Fisher, Robert (Box 37)
- The Flatlands (Box 37)
- Ford Foundation (Box 37)
- Fortas, Abe. (Box 37)
- Foster, John Stuart, Jr. (Box 37)
- Frantz, Marge (Box 37)
- Free speech - Norman Isaacs report, 1969 (Box 37)
- Free Student Union (Berkeley) (Box 37)
- Free University (Palo Alto) (Box 37)
- Freedom Houde (Leonard R. Sussman) (Box 38)
- Freedom Leadership Foundation (Box 38)
- Freedom Talk (Life Line) (Box 38)
- Mark, Hans (Box 38)
- Work folder (Box 38)
- Photographs (Box 38)
- Churchman, C. West, "On the Ethics of Large-Scale Systems,", 1966 (Box 38)
- Miscellany (Box 38)
- Miscellany (Box 39)
- Miscellany (Box 40)
- Sherriffs, Alex (Box 40)
- Siegel, Dan (Box 40)
- Sinyavsky, Andrei, and Yuri Daniel (Box 41)
- Sit-in, Berkeley, October 1968 (Box 41)
- Slate (Box 41)
- Smale, Stephen (Box 41)
- Smith, Howard K. (Box 41)
- Independent Socialist Clubs (Box 41)
- Socialist Workers Party (Box 41)
- Sontag, Raymond (Box 41)
- Sparks, Jack (Box 41)
- Spartacist League (Box 41)
- Special Opportunity Scholarship Program (Box 41)
- Spider (Box 41)
- Spitzer, Dr. R. R. (Box 41)
- Spack, Dr. Benjamin (Box 41)
- Stanford University, 1968-1969 (Box 41)
- Stanford University, 1970-1971 (Box 42)
- Stapp, Henry P. (Box 42)
- State colleges (California) (Box 42)
- Stop the Draft Week, October 1967 (Box 42)
- Strike (Berkeley), December 1966 (Box 43)
- Miscellany (Box 43)
- Smale, Stephen (Box 43)
- Sierra Club Bulletin, 1960-1965 (Box 43)
- (Box 44)
- Sierra Club Bulletin, l964-1967 (Box 44)
- Radiation Biology 830AB class (Box 44)
- Miscellany (Box 44)
- Miscellany (Box 45)
- Kerr, Clark, 1953-1965 (Box 45)
- Free Speech Movement (Edward W. Strong) (Box 45)
- Letters and personal (Box 45)
- Jones, Hardin B. - special material (Box 46)
- Bodega Bay - relation to Free Speech Movement (Box 46)
- Miscellany (Box 46)
- Citizens' response to Edward W. Strong (Box 47)
- Strong, Edward W. (Box 47)
- Atthowe, Pat (Box 47)
- Miscellany (Box 47)
- Miscellany (Box 48)
- Miscellany (Box 49)
- Free Speech Movement (Box 49)
- Free Speech Movement handouts (Box 49)
- Free Speech Movement and May 2 Movement (Box 49)
- Fulbright, J. W. (Box 49)
- Funk, Ron (Box 49)
- Galbraith, John K. (Box 49)
- Galbraith, John S. (Box 49)
- Gardner, John William (Box 49)
- Gay liberation (Box 50)
- Gilbaugh, John W. (Box 50)
- Golden Bear, Order of the (Box 50)
- Governance (Box 50)
- Governors' conference (Box 50)
- Graduate Students and Graduate Coordinating Committee (Box 50)
- Bay Guardian (Box 50)
- Harris, David (Box 50)
- Harvard University (Box 50)
- Hayden, Tom (Box 50)
- Heyman Committee (Berkeley) (Box 50)
- Heyns, Roger (Box 50)
- Hilliard, David (Box 51)
- Hitch, Charles J. (Box 51)
- Homosexuality (Box 51)
- Hoffman, Abbie (Box 51)
- Hook, Sidney (Box 51)
- House Committee on Un-American Activities (Box 51)
- Humor (Box 51)
- Hutchins, Robert M. (Box 51)
- Sensitivity (Box 51)
- Miscellany (Box 51)
- Miscellany (Box 52)
- National Council on Crime and Delinquency (Box 52)
- "Administrative Pressures and Student Political Activity at the University of California: A Preliminary Report,", 1964 (Box 52)
- Miscellany (Box 53)
- Miscellany (Box 54)
- Columbia University (Box 54)
- Combat (Box 54)
- Commoner, Dr. Barry (Box 54)
- Communique for New Politics (Box 54)
- Committee against Tuition (Berkeley) (Box 54)
- Communism, 1968-1969 (Box 54)
- Communism, 1970-1971 (Box 55)
- Richard Cotten's Conservative Viewpoint (Box 55)
- Coombs, Kenneth (Box 55)
- Congress of Racial Equality (Box 55)
- Court actions (Box 55)
- Cranston, Alan McGregor (Box 55)
- Cuba (Box 55)
- Culbert, Mike (Box 55)
- Davis, Angela, 1969-1972 (Box 56)
- Dellums, Ronald (Box 56)
- Development and Decentralization: The Administration of the University of California, 1958-1966 (Box 56)
- Dodd, Thomas J. (Box 56)
- Drugs - Discussion on LSD and marijuana (Box 57)
- Dow Chemical Company (Box 57)
- Duckles, Madeline, and women's liberation (Box 57)
- American Association of University Professors (Berkeley) (Box 57)
- Abortion, Berkeley movement to legalize (Box 57)
- Alameda County, California (Box 57)
- American Civil Liberties Union and free speech at Berkeley (Box 57)
- American Federation of Teachers (Berkeley) (Box 57)
- Agnew, Spiro T., and antiwar movement (Box 57)
- Americans for Democratic Action (Stanford and Berkeley) (Box 57)
- Anti - Vietnam War movement (Berkeley) (Box 57)
- Aptheker, Bettina and Herbert (Box 57)
- Arson (Berkeley and other Campuses) (Box 58)
- Artman, Charles E. (Box 58)
- Associated Students of the University of California (Box 58)
- Balderston, Fred (Box 58)
- Bardacke (Frank) affair (Box 58)
- Berkeley Barb and underground newspapers (Box 58)
- Berkeley Citizens United (Box 58)
- Berkeley, 1971 (Box 58)
- Newspaper Clippings, 1966-1972 (Box 59)
- California Monthly (Box 59)
- Vietnam Day Committee (Box 60)
- San Francisco State College, 1967-1969 (Box 60)
- San Francisco State College, 1969-1971 (Box 61)
- Santa Monica Evening Outlook (Box 61)
- Savio, Mario (Box 61)
- Schwartz, Professor Charles (Box 61)
- Scalapino, Robert A (Box 61)
- Schwarz, Fred (Box 61)
- Seale, Bobby (Box 61)
- Searle, John R. (Box 61)
- Selective Service System (Box 62)
- Sellers, Charles (Box 62)
- Senate hearings on internal security (Box 62)
- Sensitivity training (Box 62)
- Sex (Box 62)
- Leaflets, 1970-1971 (Box 62)
- Leaflets, 1965-1970 (Box 63)
- Notebooks, 1965-1967 (Box 64)
- Notebooks, 1945-1964 (Box 65)
- Truth about Civil Turmoil (Box 65)
- Tapp Committee (Box 65)
- Telegraph Avenue, Berkeley (Box 65)
- TenBroeck, Jacobus, and amicus curiae brief before Judge Rupert Crittenden (Box 65)
- Tocsin index (Box 65)
- Tocsin, 1965-1967 (Box 65)
- Treuhaft, Robert E. (Box 66)
- Trombley, William - clippings (Box 66)
- Tschirgi, Robert D. (Box 66)
- Tshombe, Moise (Box 66)
- Thirteenth Report Supplement of the Senate Fact finding Subcommittee on Un-American Activities (California), 1966 (Box 66)
- Tufts University (Box 66)
- Tussman College (Box 66)
- Unions (Box 66)
- University mailings (Box 66)
- Campus crime (Box 66)
- University (Berkeley) (Box 66)
- University commencements (Berkeley, Santa Cruz, Harvard), 1969 (Box 66)
- University commencements (Berkeley), 1969-1971 (Box 66)
- University centennial (Berkeley) (Box 66)
- University dormitory workers strike (Berkeley), 1971 (Box 66)
- University Faculty (California) (Box 66)
- University of California (San Diego) (Box 66)
- University of California (San Diego) (Box 67)
- University of California (Santa Cruz) (Box 67)
- University of California (Santa Barbara) (Box 67)
- Universities - Foreign (Box 67)
- Universities - U.S., 1970-1971 (Box 67)
- Center for Participant Education, the Red Family, and Edward Teller (Box 68)
- Campus disorders, 1969 (Box 68)
- Center for Participant Education (Class l39X) and Board of (Box 68)
- Educational Development (Box 68)
- Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions (Box 69)
- Charter Day, 1965-1970 (Box 69)
- Cheit, Vice Chancellor Earl F. (Box 69)
- Chicago Seven (Box 69)
- Chicago Seven riot, February 1970 (Box 69)
- Chicanos (Box 69)
- Christian World Liberation Front (Box 69)
- Church League of America (Box 70)
- Civil rights (Box 70)
- Cleaver, Eldridge (Box 70)
- Coblentz, William K. (Box 70)
- Cohelan, Jeffery (Box 70)
- Collins, Tom (Box 70)
- Colorado, University of (Box 70)
- Notebooks, 1971 (Box 70)
- Notebooks, 1968-1970 (Box 71)
- Berkeley activism, 1965-1971 (Box 72)
- Presidents Committee on Student Unrest, 1970 (Box 73)
- Progressive Labor Movement (Box 73)
- Publications, Underground (Box 73)
- Public response to university activities (Box 73)
- Radicalism at M.I.T., and University Center for Rational Alternatives, 1970 (Box 73)
- Raskin, A. H. (Box 73)
- Reagan, Ronald, 1968 - l971 (Box 73)
- Reagan, Ronald, 1966-1967 (Box 74)
- Reconstitution (Berkeley) 1 May 1970 (Box 74)
- Regents (University of California) (Box 74)
- Regents' stand on communism (Box 74)
- Reserve Officers Training Corps (Box 74)
- Responsible Citizens Aroused (Box 74)
- Richmond, California (Box 74)
- Richmond schools (Box 74)
- Riots (Box 74)
- Rock festivals (Box 75)
- Reserve Officers Training Corps (Box 75)
- Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Box 75)
- Rossman, Michael (Box 75)
- Rubin, Jerry (Box 75)
- Roudebush (Box 75)
- Camejo, Peter (Young Socialist Alliance) (Box 75)
- Campus Communist Party (Box 75)
- Campus draft opposition (Berkeley) (Box 75)
- Campus Peace Center (Berkeley) (Box 75)
- Carmichael, Stokely (Box 75)
- Cartter, Allan M. - Report, 1965 (Box 75)
- Center for Participant Education (Box 75)